SHANMUKH GORLE

+1(929) 944-5431 \diamond gorleshanmukh@gmail.com \diamond Fort Worth, TX linkedin.com/in/gorleshanmukh \diamond shanmukhgorle.dev

SUMMARY

Experienced Java full-stack developer with approximately 5 years of expertise in creating web applications for businesses using advanced frameworks and web services. A year's experience as a Scrum Master, leading a team of 4 developers.

SKILLS

Languages: Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, C
Version Control & Tools: Git, Gitlab, GitHub, Bitbucket
Testing & Automation: Python Selenium, Junit

Databases: MongoDB, SQL, Postgres
CI/CD & IaaS: GitHub Actions, Terraform
Cloud: Amazon AWS, Microsoft Azure

Web Development: Spring Boot, Angular 2+, React, Express, NodeJS, JSP, Spring MVC

Key Skills: Full-Stack Development, Application Development, Java Programming & Frameworks, MEAN/MERN Stack,

Functional Testing, Code Review, Database Design, Agile Methodology, Infrastructure Automation

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

Jan 2024 – Present Fort Worth, TX

Cognizant

• Onshore Lead with expertise in application development, team management, and cross-collaboration, overseeing offshore teams, facilitating technical problem-solving, and leading development, code reviews, and deployment activities.

Java Application Developer (Research Assistant)

October 2022 – December 2023

North Carolina Research Center (UNCC)

Kannapolis, NC

- Led the migration project, transitioning the application from Spring to Spring Boot, resulting in a 30% reduction in configuration effort and a 20% increase in developer productivity.
- Increased performance by reducing the search time of an application by over 15%, streamlining the process of uploading mass spectrometry for effective searching and comparison with an existing chemical compound database.

Member of Technical Staff - 1

November 2021 - June 2022

Athenahealth

India

India

- Contributed to the development of a Healthcare Payment Application that facilitated payment processing between US hospitals and insurance companies, achieving more than 90% code test coverage.
- Managed a team of 4 developers using agile practices, organizing Scrum events at release and sprint level, and achieved a sprint success rate of over 95%. Efficiently managed backlog creation, prioritized sprint items, and facilitated seamless communication between product owners and developers for effective story assignments.
- Acted as an integral part of the on-call rotation team, ensuring 24/7 availability to promptly address any production issues

Programmer Analyst

May 2019 - November 2021

Cognizant May 2019 –

- Developed a flight management application for pilots maintaining code test coverage exceeding 95%. Automated infrastructure creation using Terraform. Contributed to documentation, conducted reviews, performed analysis, and resolved issues.
- Played an active role in defect triage sessions, aiding in identifying and prioritizing critical issues and swiftly resolved critical defects, ensuring timely fixes.
- Mentored and trained 3 junior developers, promoting collaboration and maintaining high code standards.

AWARDS AND RECOGNITION

2021 - Attained the designation of Environment Champion through adeptly tackling resolving and documenting challenges within development environments and consistently maintaining less than 5% downtime during sprints.

2020 - Received the Cognizant Cheers Gold award for playing a critical role, showcasing exceptional ownership and leadership qualities, and a silver award for working as one.

LEADERSHIP

Managed a team of 4 developers as Team Lead and Scrum Master, ensuring successful project deliveries and Agile best practices.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer Science, University of North Carolina, Charlotte Concentration: Software, Systems & Networks

August 2022 - December 2023

GPA: 4/4

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science & Engineering, KIIT, India

May 2015 - May 2019